A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, S-Z FA394
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Strode, George K.
  - 1944 January-May, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 4, Frame 254, Box 450)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an associate director of the International Health Division (IHD). The IHD focus is to strengthen control of infectious diseases through field and laboratory work, and faces health emergencies inherent to World War II. Strode receives program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health.
    Nutrition; Public health; United States; Yellow fever; Anopheles gambiae; DDT (Insecticide); Insect baits and repellents; Malaria
  - 1944 June-December, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 4, Frame 355, Box 450)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is a director of the International Health Division (IHD). The IHD focus is to strengthen control of infectious diseases through field and laboratory work, and faces health emergencies inherent to World War II. Strode receives program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health.
    United States; Typhus fever; Nutrition; Malaria; Tropical medicine; Public health
  - Index, 1945; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Box 450, Reel M Str 4, Frame 503)
    Typhus fever; United States; Malaria; Nursing; England; Hygiene; Public health; Tuberculosis; Nutrition; Peru; Aedes aegypti; Yellow fever; Brazil; Argentina
  - 1945, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 4, Frame 530, Box 450)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is a director of the International Health Division (IHD). The IHD continues its program interests in malaria, respiratory diseases, typhus fever and yellow fever. The Division's subordinate interests include mental hygiene, syphilis, nutrition and tuberculosis. The IHD also promotes public health education with fellowships and travel grants. Strode received program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health.
    Malaria; Nursing; Aedes aegypti; Hygiene; Yellow fever; Tuberculosis; Typhus fever; Nutrition; Public health
  - Index, 1946; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 451, Reel M Str 4, Frame 748)
    27 pages, includes index by country and general country.
  - 1946, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 4, Frame 775, Box 451)
    Hygiene; India; Malaria; Medical care; Nursing; Nutrition; Pakistan; Public health; Yellow fever; United States; Tuberculosis; China; England; France; Tropical medicine; Sanitation
  - Index, 1947; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 5, Frame 1, Box 451)
    22 pages, includes index by country and general index.
  - 1947, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Box 451, Reel M Str 5, Frame 23)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is a director of the International Health Division (IHD). The IHD continues its program interests in malaria, respiratory diseases, typhus fever and yellow fever. The Division's subordinate interests include mental hygiene, syphilis, nutrition and tuberculosis. The IHD also promotes public health education with fellowships and travel grants. Strode received program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary details a survey of a Mexican health center.
    Public health; Venereal diseases; Germany; France; Epidemiology; England; Switzerland; Tropical medicine; Tuberculosis; United States; Nutrition; Nursing; Netherlands; Mexico; Medicine, Preventive; Malaria; Italy; Hygiene
  - Index, 1948; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Reel M Str 5, Frame 228, Box 451)
    9 pages, includes index by country and general index.
  - 1948, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Reel M Str 5, Frame 237, Box 451)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is a director of the International Health Division (IHD). The IHD continues its investigation and control of diseases important to the field public health. The IHD also promotes public health education with fellowships and travel grants. Strode received program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary details Strode's travels to the Middle East to survey public health programs and preventive medical research.
    Italy; Lebanon; Iran; Iraq; Greece; Hygiene; Turkey; Egypt; Sanitation; Tropical medicine; Nutrition; Public health; Malaria; Medicine, Preventive; United States; Yellow fever
  - Index, 1949; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Reel M Str 5, Frame 412, Box 451)
    10 pages, includes index by country and general index.
    Yellow fever; United States; France; Finland; Italy; Hygiene; Brazil; Switzerland; England; DDT (Insecticide); Sweden; Sanitation; Medical education; Malaria; Public health; Norway
  - 1949, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 451, Reel M Str 5, Frame 422)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is a director of the International Health Division (IHD). The IHD continues its investigation and control of diseases important to the field public health. The IHD also promotes public health education with fellowships and travel grants. Strode received program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary details surveys of Brazilian public health programs and surveys of baltic states medical education.
    Finland; France; Hygiene; Italy; Switzerland; Brazil; DDT (Insecticide); England; Sanitation; Sweden; Malaria; Medical education; Norway; Public health; United States; Yellow fever
  - Index, 1950; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 451, Reel M Str 5, Frame 596)
    18 pages, includes index by country and general index.
    Tropical medicine; Switzerland; Yellow fever; United States; France; England; Egypt; Sri Lanka; Italy; India; Hygiene; Greece; Pakistan; Nutrition; Nursing; Malaria; Sanitation; Public health
  - 1950, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 451, Reel M Str 5, Frame 614)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is a director of the International Health Division (IHD). The IHD continues its investigation and control of diseases important to the field public health. The IHD also promotes public health education with fellowships and travel grants. Strode received program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary details surveys of Indian public health programs.
    Greece; Hygiene; England; France; Malaria; Nursing; India; Italy; Public health; Sanitation; Nutrition; Pakistan; United States; Yellow fever; Switzerland; Tropical medicine; Egypt; Sri Lanka
  - Index, 1951; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 451, Reel M Str 5, Frame 808)
    7 pages, includes index by country and general index.
    Yellow fever; Public health; United States; Medical education; Nursing; Anopheles gambiae; Malaria
  - 1951 January-April, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 5, Frame 817, Box 451)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is a director of the International Health Division (IHD). The IHD continues its investigation and control of diseases important to the field public health. The IHD also promotes public health education with fellowships and travel grants. Strode received program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health.
    Malaria; Medical education; Anopheles gambiae; Yellow fever; United States; Public health; Nursing
  - Diary Duplicate, 1927 (Box 452)
    Related Archival Materials note
    Bound duplicate of set in RG 12.1
  - Diary Duplicate, 1928 (Box 452)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1929 (Box 452)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1930 (Box 452)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1931 (Box 452)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1932 (Box 453)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1933 (Box 453)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1934 (Box 453)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1935 (Box 453)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1936 (Box 453)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1937 (Box 454)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1938 January-May (Box 454)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1938 June-December (Box 454)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1939 (Box 454)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1940 (Box 455)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1941 (Box 455)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1942 (Box 455)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1943 (Box 456)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1944 (Box 456)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1945 (Box 456)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1946 (Box 457, Folder data_value_missing_498c5bb8fd8b3102beac04ca00728460)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1947 (Box 457)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1948 (Box 457)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1949 (Box 457)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1950 (Box 458)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1951 (Box 458)
- Struthers, Robert R.
  - 1947 (Box 458)
  - 1948 (Box 458)
  - 1949 (Box 459)
  - 1950 (Box 459)
  - 1951 (Box 459)
  - 1952 (Box 460)
  - 1953-1954 (Box 460)
- Sturrock, Robert Falcon
  - 1966-196 May (Box 460)
  - 1968 June-1969 (Box 460)
  - 1970-1973 (Box 460)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1966-1969 (Box 461)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1970-1973 (Box 461)
- Sweet, Winfield C.
  - 1936 (Box 462)
  - 1938-1942 (Box 462)
- Taylor, Richard M.
  Brazil
  - 1945-1948 (Box 462)
  - 1951-1952 (Box 463)
  - 1953-1954, 1956 (Box 463)
- Taylor, Ruth G.
  - 1940-1941 (Box 463)
- Tennant, Mary Elizabeth
  - 1935, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Reel M Ten 1, Frame 255, Box 464)
    The diary contains comments on the visited sites regarding public health education and facilities. Includes a list of organizations visited.
    United States; Tuberculosis; Puerto Rico; Public health; Nursing; Medical education; Hygiene; Hospitals; Dispensaries; Cuba
  - 1932, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Box 464, Reel M Ten 1, Frame 1)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. Mary Tennant is a special member of the International Health Division stationed at the Paris Office. She travels around Europe talking with professionals in the field of public health nursing. The diary documents nursing fellowships, public health nursing education and research in public health.
    Public health; Romania; Nursing; Poland; Malaria; Medical education; Hygiene; Italy; France; Hungary; Dispensaries; England; Spain; Austria; Tuberculosis; Switzerland
  - 1933, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Box 464, Reel M Ten 1, Frame 111)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. Mary Tennant working from the Paris Office and travelling around Europe is a special member of the International Health Division. The diary focuses on nursing fellowships and nursing education survey.
    Public health; Nursing; Netherlands; Medical education; Italy; Hygiene; Hungary; Germany; France; Europe; Austria; Tuberculosis; Romania; Switzerland
  - 1934, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Box 464, Reel M Ten 1, Frame 205)
    Medical education; Italy; Hygiene; Hungary; United States; Romania; Public health; Nursing; Austria; Czechoslovakia; Europe; France
  - 1935 December 27- 1936 January 10, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Box 464, Reel M Ten 1, Frame 325)
    A brief diary of Mary Tennant travels to Panama to survey nursing training and local public health facilities.
    Public health; Panama; Nursing; Dispensaries; Tuberculosis
  - 1936, Tennant, Mary Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 464, Reel M Ten 1, Frame 336)
    The 1936 diary includes Mary Tennant's surveys of public health education, facilities and general impressions of state and local nursing in East Asia and South America.
    Guatemala; Fiji; Hong Kong; Hawaii; China; Child welfare; El Salvador; Costa Rica; Medical education; Mexico; Australia; American Samoa; Nursing; Philippines; New Zealand; Nicaragua; Tonga; Public health; Tuberculosis; Tropical medicine; Hygiene; Java; Malaria
  - Visits, 1937; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 464, Reel M Ten 1, Frame 552)
    5 pages. Foreign visits indexed by place only and not by names of individuals.
  - 1937, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Box 464, Reel M Ten 1, Frame 557)
    The diary is arranged according to interview and visit and documents Mary Tennant's talks with professionals in the field of public health. During 1937, Tennant surveys public health education, gives her impressions of nursing education and public health nursing in China, and discusses nursing fellowships. Included in the diary is a proposed outline of a health center program for Japan.
    China; Brazil; Japan; Hygiene; Tuberculosis; Tropical medicine; Yellow fever; United States; Nursing; Medical education; Sanitation; Public health; Peking. Union Medical College
  - Visits, 1938; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 464, Reel M Ten 1, Frame 707)
    11 pages. Schedule of visits made by Mary Tennant; Index of interviewees.
  - 1938, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Box 464, Reel M Ten 1, Frame 718)
    The diary is arranged according to interview and visit and documents Mary Tennant's talks with professionals in the field of public health. The focus of the International Health Division in which Mary Tennant is a staff member is disease prevention and investigation of diseases important to public health. The diary details her impressions of public health nursing in Chicago, a cooperative plan for the preparation of public health nurses and the creation of a nursing training project.
    Public health; United States; Canada; Hygiene; Medical education; Nursing
  - Visits, 1939; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Box 464, Reel M Ten 1, Frame 818)
  - 1939, Tennant, Mary Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 464, Reel M Ten 1, Frame 872)
    The diary is arranged according to interview and visit and documents Mary Tennant's talks with professionals in the field of public health. The focus of the International Health Division in which Mary Tennant is a staff member is disease prevention and investigation of diseases important to public health. The diary surveys nursing education and public health nursing in the United States and Canada, her attendance at a nursing education conference and discussions regarding nursing fellows.
    Canada; Hygiene; United States; Venereal diseases; Medical education; Nursing; Public health; Tuberculosis
  - Index, 1940; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Box 464, Reel M Ten 2, Frame 1)
    9 pages.
  - 1940, Tennant, Mary Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Ten 2, Frame 10, Box 464)
    SCope and Contents note
    The diary is arranged according to interview and visit and documents Mary Tennant's talks with professionals in the field of public health. The focus of the International Health Division in which Mary Tennant is a staff member is disease prevention and investigation of diseases important to public health. The IHD withdraws from various cooperative health undertakings in Europe and focuses efforts on South America and East Asia. The diary details Tennant's impressions of nursing education and public health on her travels.
    Singapore; Public health; Dispensaries; Hawaii; Hygiene; Malaria; Medical education; Nursing; Panama; Philippines; Venezuela; Venereal diseases; United States; Tuberculosis; Sri Lanka; Brazil; Canada; Child welfare
  - Index, 1941; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Ten 2, Frame 185, Box 465)
  - 1941, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Box 465, Reel M Ten 2, Frame 199)
    The diary is arranged according to interview and visit and documents Mary Tennant's talks with professionals in the field of public health. The focus of the International Health Division in which Mary Tennant is a staff member is disease prevention and investigation of diseases important to public health. Tennant travels to India to survey various public health center facilities. The diary details her impressions of public health nursing and recommendations for nursing improvements with India collaborating with the Rockefeller Foundation.
    India; Hygiene; Nursing; Medical education; Peru; Panama; Sri Lanka; Public health; United States; Venereal diseases; Venezuela; Canada; Tuberculosis; Colombia; Chile; Ecuador; Cuba
  - Index, 1942; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Box 465, Reel M Ten 2, Frame 511)
  - 1942, Tennant, Mary Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 465, Reel M Ten 2, Frame 524)
    The diary is arranged according to interview and visit and documents Mary Tennant's talks with professionals in the field of public health. The focus of the International Health Division in which Mary Tennant is a staff member is disease prevention and investigation of diseases important to public health. Tennant travels to South America and gives her impressions of nursing in Rio De La Plata and Andean Region.
    Chile; Canada; Ecuador; Colombia; Peru; Public health; Brazil; Argentina; Nursing; Medical education; Nutrition; Hospitals; Haiti; Jamaica; Hygiene; Uruguay; United States; Tuberculosis; Sanitation; Venezuela
  - Index, 1943; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 465, Reel M Ten 2, Frame 792)
  - 1943, Tennant, Mary Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 465, Reel M Ten 2, Frame 801)
    The diary is arranged according to interview and visit and documents Mary Tennant's talks with professionals in the field of public health. The focus of the International Health Division in which Mary Tennant is a staff member is disease prevention and investigation of diseases important to public health. Tennant travels to South America to survey nursing education, public health facilities and to administer proposals for public health nursing. The diary also includes a proposed nursing education fund for Iran.
    Panama; Nursing; Medical education; Jamaica; Venezuela; United States; Tuberculosis; Public health; Hygiene; Ecuador; Colombia
  - Index, 1944; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 465, Reel M Ten 3, Frame 1)
  - 1944, Tennant, Mary Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 465, Reel M Ten 3, Frame 15)
    The diary is arranged according to interview and visit and documents Mary Tennant's talks with professionals in the field of public health. The focus of the International Health Division in which Mary Tennant is a staff member is disease prevention and investigation of diseases important to public health. The diary details the Rockefeller Foundation nursing program in Brazil and fellowships. The diary includes, "Report of Poliomyelitis Epidemic, 1944 Quito, Ecuador."
    Colombia; Chile; Canada; Brazil; Argentina; Peru; Public health; Trinidad; Nursing; Mexico; Medical education; Malaria; Jamaica; Hygiene; Haiti; Ecuador; United States; Tuberculosis; Venezuela; Uruguay
  - Index, 1945; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Ten 3, Frame 200, Box 465)
    19 pages.
  - 1945, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Reel M Ten 3, Frame 219, Box 465)
    The diary is arranged according to interview and visit and documents Mary Tennant's talks with professionals in the field of public health. The focus of the International Health Division in which Mary Tennant is a staff member is disease prevention and investigation of diseases important to public health. In 1945, Tennant becomes an assistant director of the IHD. The diaries includes public health facilities and school tours, various diaries of South American travels to survey access and promote local and state public health nursing programs. Tennant also travels to Europe and documents a tuberculosis survey in Iceland, nursing education in Sweden and Norway and reports on public health work in Finland.
    Nutrition; Panama; Norway; Nursing; Jamaica; Nicaragua; Hygiene; Iceland; Sweden; Tuberculosis; Portugal; Public health; Venereal diseases; Venezuela; Holland (Netherlands: Province); United States; France; Haiti; Epidemiology; Finland; El Salvador; England; Denmark; Ecuador; Child welfare; Colombia; Belgium; Canada
  - Index, 1946; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Reel M Ten 3, Frame 465, Box 466)
    21 pages.
  - 1946, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Reel M Ten 3, Frame 486, Box 466)
    The diary is arranged according to interview and visit and documents Mary Tennant's talks with professionals in the field of public health. The focus of the International Health Division in which Mary Tennant is a staff member is disease prevention and investigation of diseases important to public health. Tennant travels to Europe to survey hospital accommodations in Prague, outline a program of public health and social work study and report on nursing in Czechoslovakia during World War II and the occupation.
    Venezuela; World War II; Tuberculosis; Turkey; United States; Venereal diseases; Public health; Nutrition; Nursing; Canada; Colombia; Communicable diseases; Cyprus; Czechoslovakia; Egypt; England; France; Haiti; Hungary; Hygiene; India; Malaria
  - Index, 1947; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Reel M Ten 3, Frame 744, Box 466)
    25 pages.
  - 1947, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Box 466, Reel M Ten 3, Frame 769)
    The diary is arranged according to interview and visit and documents Mary Tennant's talks with professionals in the field of public health. The focus of the International Health Division in which Mary Tennant is a staff member is disease prevention and investigation of diseases important to public health. Tennant travels to Asia and South America. The diary details a survey of the Rockefeller Foundation Indian public health program, field studies of public health nursing in China Japan and Korea. The present status of former Rockefeller Foundation nursing fellows is included as well.
    India; Hygiene; Hawaii; DDT (Insecticide); Medical education; Malaria; Korea; Japan; Philippines; Nursing; United States; Tuberculosis; Venezuela; Venereal diseases; China; Colombia; Public health; Canada
  - Index, 1948; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Box 466, Reel M Ten 4, Frame 1)
  - 1948, Tennant, Mary Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Ten 4, Frame 15, Box 466)